Okay, now where does the risk model come in?
那么风险模型放哪呢？
Well, we discussed previously that if we put
我们之前讨论过
the quantity representing the mean in the objective,
如果将表示均值的量放入目标函数中
one option is to place a constraint on the portfolio variance.
一种做法是对投资组合方差进行约束
We already know how to calculate the portfolio covariance matrix using a risk model.
我们已经知道如何使用风险模型计算投资组合协方差
All we do to get the portfolio variance is
计算投资组合方差的方法与
the same thing we did back when we were calculating the portfolio variance before.
之前计算投资组合方差的方法是一样的
We write the portfolio variance as
投资组合方差等于
the weight vector transpose times the covariance matrix times the weight vector.
权重向量的转置乘以协方差矩阵 再乘以权重向量
That's great, so let's limit portfolio risk.
我们对投资组合风险加以限制
We'll say it has to be below some value.
假设它必须小于某个值
We're already most of the way there.
就快要搞定了
You might have one very reasonable question at this point which is,
这时候 你也许有个很合理的疑问
how do we know what value to set as our limit on portfolio variance?
怎么确定投资组合方差的上限值？
Well, this value represents the tolerable variance of
这个值表示每个时段（在此时段运行优化）的
your portfolio returns per time period over which you run the optimization.
投资组合收益率可以忍受的方差
As a portfolio manager,
作为投资组合经理
this is usually given to you,
通常这个值是给定的
but where does it come from?
但是它来自何处？
Well, it represents a business decision.
它代表一种商业决策
Remember that the investment portfolio we're designing represents a product,
记住 我们设计的投资组合代表一种产品
which is sold to investors.
该产品会卖给投资者
When investors are shopping around,
当投资者在选购时
they typically compare products with different risk return characteristics.
他们通常会比较具有不同风险收益率特性的产品
What numbers are reasonable?
什么样的值比较合理？
The general stale volatility can be observed from the market itself,
我们可以通过市场本身观察一般的波动性
for example, from an index like the S&amp;P 500.
例如根据 S&amp;P 500 等指数
The annualized standard deviation of the S&amp;P
S&amp;P 500 在 100 年期间的
500 over 100 years has been 12 percent or so.
年化标准差为 12% 左右
So, people benchmark their risk against that.
人们以该值为基准设定风险上限
If you look at indices that measure hedge fund industry performance,
查看衡量对冲基金行业业绩的指标后
you see volatility of around four to five percent.
会发现波动性约为 4%-5%
So, if I'm running a hedge fund,
假设我管理的是对冲基金
there's business risk associated with setting
如果我的产品投资组合风险与这些值差别很大
my product's portfolio risk to something dramatically different from those numbers.
那么就存在一定的商业风险
Over time, there's been evolutionary convergence to the levels of risk,
随着时间的推移 风险水平趋于稳定
that makes sense given the market for these products.
对于这些产品的市场来说是合理的
If you work in a really big firm,
如果你在一家大型企业工作
and you're managing a small portfolio,
并且管理的是很小的投资组合
you will likely receive this number as a mandate,
很有可能会收到硬性风险上限值
such as you can't lose more than 10 percent.
例如不能超过 10%
So, you can calibrate your risk so that you are comfortable with where you
你可以调整你的风险水平
are currently in relation to that maximum loss threshold.
使当前风险水平相对于这个最大损失阈值来说比较能接受